http://www.generalaviationnews.com/privacy-policy/

GENERAL AVIATION NEWSNewsAccidentsFirst flight bends homebuilt planeThe pilot’s failure to maintain airplane control during landing, which resulted in the right tire contacting the runway first followed by the left wing.Plane hits fence after student fails to relinquish controls to CFIThe student pilot's improper landing flare, which resulted in a bounced landing, and the flight instructor’s delayed remedial action and the student’s failure to relinquish control, which resulted in a runway overrun and impact with a fence.Trike pilot runs out of gas over desertThe total loss of engine power due to fuel exhaustion, which resulted from the pilot's inadequate preflight fuel inspection.Student pilot’s selfie ends in forced landing in waterThe student pilot's inadvertent movement of the fuel shutoff switch to the “off” position while attempting to take a picture of himself, which resulted in a total loss of engine power due to fuel starvation and a subsequent ditching in open water.Read All Accident ArticlesAircraft NewsPicture of the Day: What’s not to like?Mary Ann Lebold submitted this photo and note: The webcams at Lenhardt Airpark (7S9) in Oregon were recently updated. Here’s what things looked like on Dec. 1, 2020, about 2 p.m. What’s not to like?"SeaMax now assembled in U.S.The new assembly operations are at Daytona Beach International Airport in Florida.Tecnam’s P2010 TDI certifiedFAA certification is expected to follow the recent EASA certification.New study could improve how aircraft fly in gusty winds“We know birds cope amazingly well in conditions which challenge engineered air vehicles of a similar size but, until now, we didn’t understand the mechanics behind it."Read all Aircraft ArticlesAirportsAre GA airports red-headed stepchildren?It is not enough for us to say, “we were here first” or “it’s not our fault you don’t understand the value of an airport.”Minnesota airport savedA grant from the Recreational Aviation Foundation will remove trees encroaching on the runway, stirring threats to close the airport.Oregon’s Aurora Airport, area fire districts team up for trainingThe training first responders receive at KUAO is vital to the community's safety.Clay Lacy expands at KOXCThe company will invest $20 million to build a new FBO, and maintenance, repair and overhaul facility, bringing 100 new jobs to Connecticut.Read All Airport StoriesAvionics & InstrumentsUpgraded avionics for 2021 A5sThe Garmin G3X Touch flight display is a new option on 2021 ICON A5 Limited Edition aircraft.BendixKing expands autopilot certification listAeroCruze 230 is now available for more than 35 aircraft platforms, including Baron, Bonanza, Mooney, Piper Malibu, Mirage, Seneca and Seminole, Twin Cessna, and others. Dynon SkyView certified for twin-engine aircraftDynon's first approval for a twin-engine aircraft is for the Piper Seneca.Avidyne update support multi-tasking"The IFD100 app can now be displayed on a split screen with other apps that support multitasking."Read all Avionics & Instrument storiesFlight TrainingReal Pilot Story: Pressure Over the AtlanticStep into the cockpit with pilot Kerry McCauley as he tells the tale of his harrowing flight across the Atlantic.
Gold Seal to reopen COVID Relief Program100 student pilots adversely affected by the pandemic will receive free enrollment in the company's ground school.Cirrus SR20 sim introducedThe ALSIM flight training device reproduces the SR20 cockpit and flight deck.Picture of the Day: Flying 50 years and still learningWayne Kyle submitted this photo and note: "Larry Sears (left), Brandon Areys, and Wayne Kyle with a Bonanza A-36 at Telluride Regional Airport in Colorado, where we were participating in a mountain flying course. I'm 81 years old, been flying 50 years, and still learning!"Read all Flight Training ArticlesAll NewsOpinionAsk Paul by Paul McBrideAsk Paul: Should I buy a plane that hasn’t been flown in two years?What should I be concerned with when buying an airplane that hasn't been flown in two years?Ask Paul: Should we replace the pistons or change oil?I suspect that the blow-by is caused by glazed cylinder walls. This could possibly be a result of improper break-in, so let's begin there.Ask Paul: Can I permanently remove the vacuum pump?There is no problem removing the vacuum pump drive from the engine — and there are actually two options for you.Why is my engine backfiring?I believe you are hearing the pops is because something has a crack in it.Human Factors by Jeffrey MadisonFrequency changeWhen it comes to radio communication between flying objects, the single most important thing a pilot can do is be on the right frequency.A tool of the tradeThe Leatherman multi-tool is one I’ve seen many a pilot sport. Apparently, it’s so well loved it’s even found its way into reports to NASA's Aviation Safety Reporting System.Inattention to detailInattention to detail can lead to accidents.Now that’s something to get excited aboutExcitement while flying can be good and bad.Of Wings & Things by Frederick A. JohnsenMcBizjet: A beautiful also-ranThe aircraft looked very much like a scaled down commercial jetliner, with four individually podded engines suspended from pylons in a fashion reminiscent of the Boeing 707.Bomber escort failed, but chin turret scoredGunship versions of the B-17 were seen as one answer to the scourge of German fighter attacks.GA envisioned a plane for everyone after World War IIThe optimistic postwar brochures from general aviation manufacturers reveal a mix of confidence and dreams that played out with varying degrees of success.The Wilder WildcatDuring World War II, General Motors shifted gears from making cars to building warbirds.
Politics for Pilots by Jamie BeckettThe gift of flightWhat if your significant other, your child, or your best friend found they’d been gifted with an opportunity to fly?The Age of Discovery never endsAll of us who fly have been verbally battered by those who are too constrained in their own thinking to see a bigger, better life for themselves. I believe, therefore, I can’tIt’s time to do away with the preconceived notion of not being able to solve our own problems.Life really is all about perspectiveThe gift of flight, the willingness to confront a challenge and overcome it, is far more important than simply achieving the altitude to have a better view.SPLOG by Dan JohnsonA different 2020 surgeIf I tell you that Part 103 ultralights are selling exceptionally well during COVID-19, would you believe it? I don’t blame you if you don’t — most would agree with you … but all the naysayers are wrong.Up or down? How flies the LSA industry in this strange year?The light aircraft industry appears to be surviving the COVID-19 mess better than expected. That means better health for the industry and more smiles for pilots. Crowds flock to Midwest LSA Expo 2020Despite the upheaval of COVID-19, it appears affordable aviation is doing surprisingly well and I found pilots highly enthusiastic about their flying.The latest on the FAA’s proposed changes to LSAAn NPRM is not going to be forthcoming soon. Instead, the agency is preparing for a full internal review of the proposals, known as LSA 2023.Touch & Go by Ben SclairAre GA airports red-headed stepchildren?It is not enough for us to say, “we were here first” or “it’s not our fault you don’t understand the value of an airport.”Trouble in paradiseBecause the civil and military operations at Dillingham co-exist so well, the Army would very much like to continue to allow civilian access to the field.Give him 56 days and he’ll become a private pilotFirst flight lesson was Aug. 21, followed by his first solo on Sept. 1. He passed his written exam on Sept. 29 and passed his check ride on Oct. 16.Do we need another aviation organization?I’m not cynical by nature so I feel a bit out of sorts with this column. My normal state is the belief that people far smarter than I do the hard work of sorting out the details for this type of idea.Visser’s Voice by Ben VisserTips to improve fuel efficiency in your airplaneThe principals for improving gas mileage in an aircraft are optimizing engine operation, minimizing weight, reducing aerodynamic drag, and improving operation parameters. Multigrade vs. single grade oil: Which is better for your engine?Changing the oil at least three times a year or every 50 hours (if you have an oil filter) is one of the two most important things you can do to protect your engine.A better way to change oilOil pans and drain plugs are often "perfectly" located so that it is almost impossible to get to them without burning your hands, as well as spilling oil everywhere.Engine Break-in 101Follow these tips to break-in your engine the right way.EventsClassifiedsPlace Classified AdMoreAboutHow Do IAdvertiseContact UsWriter’s GuidelinesPhotographer’s GuidelinesDigital EditionsGeneral Aviation NewsSUN ’n FUN TodaySubscribePhoto of the daySee all photos of the daySubmit Your Picture of the Day
Who we are
Our website address is: generalaviationnews.com.
What personal data we collect and why we collect it
Comments
When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.
An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.
Media
If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.
Contact forms
General Aviation News use Gravity Forms and ActiveCampaign to create contact and subscription forms. Data, such as email address, phone number, and mailing address are collected, stored and used to facilitate proper communication.
Cookies
If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.
If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.
When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.
If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.
Embedded content from other websites
Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.
These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracking your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.
Analytics
General Aviation News uses both Jetpack and Google Analytics for visitor analytics.
Who we share your data with
General Aviation News uses SimpleCirc for subscription management as well as Stripe and Quickbooks Online for credit card/payment processing. Certain personal information needed to process payments is transferred to these vendors.
We may use AdvertServe (Renegade Internet, Inc. service) to display ads on our site; this service may use cookies to serve ads based on your prior visits to our website and other websites. AdvertServe allow users to control their privacy via the AdvertServe Privacy Shield. You can manage those settings here.
Personally identifiable information beyond what is collected by the services listed about, Jetpack or Google Analytics is not shared with any person or organization. Aggregated, anonymized data is collected and assembled for marketing/purposes purposes.
How long we retain your data
If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.
For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.
What rights you have over your data
If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.
Where we send your data
Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.
Your contact information
For any Privacy-related queries, contact Ben Sclair, President, Flyer Media, PO Box 39099, Lakewood, WA 98496 or 253-471-9888 x2 or ben@generalaviationnews.com.
Additional information
How we protect your data
What data breach procedures we have in place
The General Aviation News website is hosted at WPEngine and utilizes their infrastructure for protection of data.
Last updated: August 8, 2018
Recent Comments
JimC on Plane hits fence after student fails to relinquish controls to CFIDan F on Plane hits fence after student fails to relinquish controls to CFIWayne Elson on Real Pilot Story: Pressure Over the AtlanticMiami Mike on Ask Paul: Should I buy a plane that hasn’t been flown in two years?JimH in CA on First flight bends homebuilt planeBrian on Ask Paul: Should I buy a plane that hasn’t been flown in two years?JimH in CA on Ask Paul: Should I buy a plane that hasn’t been flown in two years?
Thank you to our online partners
